They are here!
Maybe you're asking while you're seeing
what I'm seeing right now.
Maybe you're asking yourself,
"how many times have I watched this?
Is there anything new?
Is there any new story?"
We love you, Ferell brothers.
Is this all I will see?
Well, don't worry,
because this is not my story.
Oh my, the sun is already high.
Mother?
Father?
- Oh, my child.
- Why didn't you wake me up?
My child, you were sleeping soundly.
We didn't wake you up so you can rest well.
Here, taste this.
Tell me if it's delicious already.
Okay, Mother.
- Is it delicious?
- It's good, Mother,
but there's something missing.
- Does it still lack something?
- It needs a little adjusting.
Oh, okay. I'll leave it up to you.
- Yes, Mother.
- Okay, you can take charge.
She's becoming an expert now.
Did you sleep well last night, my child?
Was it okay?
When we checked on you
it seems you were having a nightmare.
Not really, Father.
You're something else.
I dreamt about the book I was reading.
About what?
It's about boys, right?
Of course not, Father.
Here you are, denying to death,
even when we saw you talking in your sleep.
You said, "Dave, I love you, Dave.
Don't leave me, Dave..."
Hey Federico, stop teasing your daughter.
She might get mad and end up crying again.
Mother, I'm no longer a crybaby.
I'm a grown woman.
I also have dreams
and a heart that is ready to love.
Wow.
Hey Florencia, stop it.
What do you mean by "grown woman"?
Do you want me to pinch your groin?
And what's this "heart that is ready to love"
are you talking about?
Hey, you, once I find out
that you're flirting around,
I will shave your head.
Lydia, just relax.
What she's saying is right.
She's a grown woman already,
she's no longer a kid.
The earlier we accept it, the better.
But, Florence, once you flirt around,
you should promise me,
you'll introduce that guy to us
if you decide to flirt around.
Then let's see if he deserves
to be flirted with.
There you go...
You're tolerating your daughter,
that's why your heart is reacting that way.
Just take it easy.
Because, Mother and Father,
why would I flirt around
if I still have a lot of dreams
I want to achieve?
I want to finish college
so I can get a decent job.
And once I have a good salary,
I'll ask you to stop selling cooked food.
That way, you don't have to wake up early
to go to the market
and you won't get tired cutting
and saute-ing onions.
And then we'll relax,
and then we'll watch movies,
right, Father and Mother?
And one more thing,
we will go swimming in Boracay Island,
or we'll stroll around Spain
por ejemplo saying good evening,
good day, or eating delicious food in Italy.
Good evening, it's delicious!
Right, Mother?
Or we can have our pictures taken
in Eiffel Tower in Paris, bonjour!
Enchante!
That's our plan, Mother.
That's never-ending drowning with happiness.
Mother?
Did I say something you don't like?
Don't you want to go to Europe?
- Would you rather go to America?
- No...
No, my child.
That's okay.
Everything's okay.
I don't know what I did,
because I was blessed by God
with a good daughter.
Thank you.
Mother, you're something else.
Federico, why don't you join us?
It's okay, you can go ahead.
- Federico?
- Here you go.
Florence Dela Cruz, there's a letter for you.
Mother, there's a letter.
- Is that for her?
- What's that letter?
That's the...
- That's today?
- That's for today.
Florence Dela Cruz?
Mister, there's a letter for me?
Do you want me to repeat it?
One more time.
Florence Dela Cruz, here's a letter for you.
Come on, Mother, Father.
- One more time.
- Where are we going?
- Where?
- What's happening?
- Here?
Here and then we'll go back again?
- Let's go, Father.
- What's going on, Florence?
- I'm getting confused now.
- Mister...
Is there a letter for me?
I'll do it again.
No need, Mister. That's enough.
- Here you go.
- There's a letter...
The letter...
My child, Florence.
Is that the result
of your college admission test?
Is that it?
Yes, Mother,
it's a letter from Gyronella University?
Florence, do you need a chair?
Why don't you sit down first?
You might get dizzy.
Yes, have a seat first.
Don't open it yet.
- Sit down first.
- That was fast.
My child, always remember,
whatever happens, it's okay.
It's really okay.
Don't be nervous, Florence. It's okay.
You're overreacting, Mother.
I'm sorry, my child.
That's okay.
I'll talk to her.
Florence, there are other opportunities.
Maybe it's okay if our choice
is just the second or third university.
That's okay, right?
Well, Mother, Father...
- I got accepted!
- What? You got accepted!
My daughter got accepted!
She got accepted!
Neighbors, Florence got accepted into the GU!
Congratulations!
Yes!
There you go...
Still nothing?
- Nothing?
- Go ahead and sit down.
- I'll take care of it.
- Don't worry! Go ahead and eat.
What do you need? Fork?
- Come on and eat.
- Hello?
- Hello? Still nothing?
- Just go ahead and eat.
This is my world.
Just like my family,
the contents of our hearts are the same.
Simple joys.
We have no plans for world domination
or expand our sphere of influence
in Eastern Europe.
With us, even if Russia declares a war,
we won't lose hope.
We'll always fight.
Hello...
- Here you go, Mr. Federico.
- Let me.
Thank you.
Hello? There...
- Our dear friends...
- Our dear friends!
Just a second.
There's something I want to tell you.
I just want to tell you
that the success of my daughter
is our success too.
I hope she'll serve as
an inspiration to all of us,
because there's nothing wrong
with dreaming, right?
That's right.
Even if we lose everything.
Even if the trials of destiny
are thrown at us,
they can never steal from us
our right to dream, right?
Right?
Let's dream of a beautiful tomorrow
for our loved ones.
- Alright?
- Yes.
That's why...
This is for Florence.
- For Florence.
- For Florence!
And this is for all of us.
- Yes, for all of us.
- Yes, for all of us!
Federico?
What happened?
- Father?
- Move aside.
- Move aside!
- Call an ambulance.
Help him!
- Move aside.
- Move aside!
We still have money left.
I also called your grandfather.
He said he'll help us out.
And even our relatives in Cebu,
they'll be giving money.
The barangay captain
said she'll apply your father
to the medical aid program of the mayor.
But, Florence, I'm sorry.
I have to ask you to take charge
of our food business.
You take charge of delivering food
to the construction site.
I don't want to lose that income.
We can add that to
your father's after-surgery expenses
and the money we need for medicines.
We can handle this, my child.
We can do this.
We'll fight.
We can do this, Mother.
We will fight and we will win,
that's for sure.
I'll go ahead.
Bye, Florence. Take care.
Thank you, Mister, enjoy!
Miss, would you like some cooked meals?
This is delicious.
No, thank you.
Okay.
Let's hurry, we might get wet in the rain.
Mister, this is for you. For you, Mister.
And this, Mister, this one is yours.
Here, that's two orders, please.
But credit is not allowed at the moment.
Father needs medicine and money
for his operation,
so if it's okay, pay cash for now.
Did you cook this, Florence?
Yes.
Are you doubting the taste?
Don't worry, Mother taught me everything,
so I'm sure it's as delicious.
If you don't like it, I'll refund your money.
Florence.
What's this for?
We all pitched in for your father.
It's not much,
but we hope this can help Federico.
Thank you. I won't say no to this.
This is a big help for us.
By the way, here's your rice, Mister.
Here you go, Mister. Thank you.
Florence?
Mr. Dencio.
How are you?
How's Federico?
Well, he's fighting but don't worry,
he can handle that.
You're the one doing that now?
Yes.
I'm sorry, I don't have extra funds,
but the reason
why I'm looking for you is that,
I have a side hustle for you.
Side hustle?
All you have to do is cook delicious food.
I know you're a very good cook,
so you can do that.
Where will I cook?
In the Ferell household.
You just have to cook for the children.
Do you know the Ferells?
They're one of the richest families
here in Levante.
And I'm sure they pay a high salary,
and that can be a big help
for your needs right now.
That's true, Mr. Dencio.
Is there anyone who doesn't know the Ferells?
I think they are the richest family
here in Levante.
And what I know,
their levels of riches are different.
But is that all you know about the Ferells?
Why, Mr. Dencio?
Is there something I need to know
about the Ferells?
Are they weird?
Do they eat the human heart
or internal organs?
Not really.
They're just like us, they eat, sleep,
they get sad, and cry,
but of course,
the rich people think differently
compared to us, who are at the bottom.
What do you mean, Mr. Dencio?
Ferell...
Let me search for it.
This is the first time
I got insulted this way
by the grandchildren of Don Ferell.
I will never forget this!
And I will tell everybody
that the worst thing
that can happen to a chef
is to cook for the Ferells.
I will shout it out to ban them
by all the chefs.
Ping, ping, ping!
What?
Mr. Dencio, why should we continue?
If the chefs couldn't stand a chance,
how can I?
Just relax, that's why I'm here, right?
So what if they don't get you?
Will you lose anything?
But if they choose you,
then the problem is solved.
You know, there's a saying,
you have everything to lose
and nothing to gain.
It's the other way around, Mr. Dencio,
you have nothing to lose
but everything to gain.
See?
I know that you know what is right,
that's why, this is easy for you.
You can do this, Florence.
Just give it a try.
Just go in. Wait for me.
I'll just park the car.
- Okay, Mr. Dencio.
- All right.
You should close your mouth.
Something bad might happen to you.
I'm sorry.
This mansion is beautiful and it's so big.
Are you the one referred by Dencio?
Yes. I'd like to apply as a cook
for the Ferells.
Follow me.
Walk this way.
So this is the kitchen
and this will be your area.
Now, I will be honest with you, Miss...
Florence. It's Florence Dela Cruz.
Alright, Ms. Florence Dela Cruz.
I don't easily give a chance to anyone
to be a cook for the Ferells.
I go through a long process of recruitment.
Usually, highly recommended by people
in the culinary scenes.
And at least, the very least,
who has worked for a couple of years
in the top restaurants.
It looks like no one stays long, right?
I'm sorry.
I saw the video of a chef
and if I'm not mistaken,
they are cursing the Ferells.
Well, at least you know why I'm so desperate.
So desperate that I'm willing
to take a chance on you,
who is a nobody.
That's what we need in life,
a chance to make a difference.
One chance to change the world
and one chance to start a revolution.
That's why, don't waste your one chance.
After all, it's not every day
that you're given a chance
to cook for one of the most
influential families in Levante.
Now, cook me your best recipe.
Prove to me that you deserve
to be a cook in this mansion.
Prove to me that you can cook
for the grandchildren of Don Ferell.
Okay, I'll prove that I can cook
What are you waiting for?
Do you have an apron?
I'll just get back to you.
Just a moment.
In a few minutes, you'll be able to
taste this delicious food that I cooked.
Who are you?
Don Ferell!
Is there anything you need, Sir?
By the way, she is Florence Dela Cruz.
She's applying as a cook for the children.
Isn't she too young?
Who recommended her?
Well, it's Dencio who recommended her.
Since we still haven't found a chef,
given the rumors about your grandchildren,
I'll try her out.
Maybe we can hire her
while we still can't find a cook
with more credentials.
So, Florence Dela Cruz?
I'm sorry if I surprised you
because when I saw you,
I remembered someone.
Never mind...
That's okay.
Even my father mistakes me
for Marian Rivera...
and Bea Alonzo on this side.
That's just a joke.
It's just a joke.
That's also a joke.
You're a funny girl, Florence.
You can call me Grandpa Garp.
Because if you call me Don,
people might think that we are characters
from an old drama series.
That's for sure!
And if I'm not mistaken,
Serafica here is making you audition.
But with what I'm smelling,
it looks like your cooking skill passed.
Serafica, can I be a judge of the new chef
because I also want to taste
Ms. Dela Cruz's cooking?
Of course, Don Ferell.
No problem.
And I think it would be best that you decide
if she deserves to be hired as a cook
for the Ferell family.
What is that?
We call that Le Balbacua
de Familia Dela Cruz.
That's my father's recipe
which his father passed on to him
when he was still living in Tabunok.
Oh, from the mountains?
No, not from the mountains, it's Tabunok.
It's one of the most beautiful places
to visit in Cebu.
Have you been to Cebu?
If you have time I'll take you there and,
you know,
the beaches there are beautiful.
It's so blue
and there are beautiful water resorts,
there are slides, places like that,
Granda Garp.
Oh, I mean, Don Ferell...
Don Ferell, I think you should
taste what Ms. Florence cooked,
so we'd know if she deserves
to be a cook in this household.
What are we waiting for?
Don Ferell?
Are you all right?
What have you done?
What did you put in what you cooked?
Huh? I didn't put anything there.
Get out!
I'm so sorry, Don Ferell.
Maybe you're not used
to that kind of cooking.
I knew it was a mistake.
The moment she stepped into this house,
I just knew there was a mistake because I...
Actually...
This thing is very good.
It reminded me of the cooking of my wife.
This is very good.
It's very, very, very good.
Are you sure, Don Ferell?
Yes, I was just surprised.
I wasn't expecting
that I'd be able to taste again
a food cooked deliciously
like how my wife used to cook.
So I guess you can say I'm impressed.
You have a talent for cooking
and from what I can smell,
you cook from the heart.
So if you'll accept it,
I want to say that you can now
be the cook for my family.
What?
It means you're hired, Miss.
Really? Yeah! Thank you, Sir!
Ms. Florence, please.
Behave yourself.
Don't worry, Don Ferell.
I will orient Ms. Florence
on how to act properly
around you and the children.
Just give me one week to train her.
No need. She can start right away.
And I think it's better if she meets the kids
because after all,
she'll be cooking for them.
Of course, Sir.
I will call all of them.
Tell them I'll meet them in the garden.
Yes, Sir. Of course, right away.
This is good.
Thank you so much, Grandpa Garp.
This is a big help to my family,
and I'm excited to meet the kids.
I'm sure you'll like them, too.
Tristan, your grandpa wants to see you.
Aldus, your grandpa is waiting in the garden.
Troy, your grandpa is in the garden,
waiting now.
Owen, please, go to the garden now.
Just be patient with Serafica.
She can be very strict sometimes,
but that's because she takes care of us well.
But don't worry, she's nice.
She's very loyal to our family.
And she's been with us for so many years now,
she will take care of all of your needs.
She's kind, she let me audition
to be your cook.
Well, your timing is perfect,
we do need a cook for my grandchildren.
You're so nice,
you love your grandchildren so much
and you personally take care of them.
Well, what's the sense of all the wealth
that I have
if I won't be able to be with my family?
One more thing, I'm already old.
I won't stay long in this world, Florence.
So might as well spend it with them.
Don't talk that way.
I'm sure you'll have more time to spend
with your grandchildren.
And one more thing,
I'm sure that all your grandchildren
are so cute.
You be the judge.
Oh, they're here.
So you're here.
Where is Nero?
Right there, Grandpa.
Nero!
Good catch, Grandson.
This is Florence.
Now that you've met Florence,
I want all of you to be good to her
because starting tomorrow,
she'll start to cook for us.
Don't worry, Grandpa, we'll be good to her.
Assuming she's a good cook.
I'm sure of that.
So, Florence, you are officially hired.
Is that all, Grandpa?
I still have to finish something.
Okay, you can go.
- Bye, Florence.
- Bye.
Good luck!
Good luck.
It looks like they're all nice,
so there won't be any problem.
What are you saying?
You'll be cooking in the Ferell's mansion?
In the mansion of the richest family
in Levante?
Do you think your father will agree to that?
How did you get that job?
Because of Mr. Dencio.
He is Father's friend, who always hangs out
at the construction site.
It was him who told me
that the Ferells need a cook,
and he recommended me.
Of course, Mother, I gave it a try,
since I've got nothing to lose, right?
I wasn't expecting that I'd pass,
because when I cooked
Father's special Balbacua,
Don Ferell was so impressed.
Even though, Florence.
We can provide for your father's needs.
No... Well, you still can't work
with that Ferell's.
Mother, the salary is 40,000 pesos
every month.
When will you start?
Do you agree now?
No. Still a no.
Mother, think about it,
40,000 pesos every month.
That's four-zero thousand.
That would be a big help for us, Mother,
especially for Father.
That's why, I don't want
to turn down the offer.
It's not that, my child.
What about your studies?
You're supposed to start studying
at the university after the vacation.
What about your dreams?
I will just apply again next year.
What?
You'll give up the scholarship you received?
Florence.
I appreciate you helping out
with your Father's situation,
but that's not your obligation.
If there's someone who should find a way,
that's us, your parents, who should do it.
Yes, I understand that, Mother.
But even if I'm a scholar in GU,
I still need money
for my expenses while studying,
like money for my allowance,
transportation fares, and for projects.
That's expensive, Mother.
And now that we are a bit tight on budget,
do you think I'd like to add up
to our expenses?
We're now finding ways to pay
for Father's treatment, right?
I understand you, Florence.
I appreciate your initiatives, but...
Mother, believe me or not,
I've thought about this carefully.
I have made my decision.
This is what I want to do.
Mother, please don't get mad at me.
It's not that I'm mad, my child.
Maybe... Maybe I'm just annoyed
because I'm feeling so helpless
in this situation.
Imagine, it's us, your parents,
who are a hindrance to your dreams.
Mother, my dream is to have
a happy and complete family.
Because what would I do
with being successful in life
if you and Father are not by my side, right?
And, Mother, I can apply again next year.
With my intelligence,
I'm sure someone will get me.
Someone will accept me, Mother.
If GU won't accept me,
then I'll apply to UP, or DLSU, ADMU, or PIS.
Mother, there are a lot of opportunities,
but what's important now
is all hands on deck for Father.
Okay...
I will agree, but on one condition.
The moment you have a hard time
in that mansion,
you'll leave that place as soon as possible
and come home.
- Understood?
- Yes, Mother.
- Is that a promise?
- Yes, Mother, that's a promise.
Cross my heart, even if lightning strikes me,
or a crocodile eats me,
I promise that to you, Mother.
- That's a promise?
- Promise!
Very good.
- Thank you, Mother.
- Take care of yourself there, my child.
Take care.
Is it just me?
Or I find our new cook cute?
There you go again
with your flirty ways, Aldus.
Will you go after our new cook, Bro?
Did I say I'll fall for her?
All I'm saying is she's cute.
Be careful, Aldus, that's where it starts.
At first, you'll find someone cute,
and after that,
you'll think of something else.
And before you know it,
you're trapped already with her charms.
How about you, Nero?
It's like I'm watching
a romantic comedy earlier.
The scene was in slow motion,
and as she was falling,
Nero was there just in time.
Not a second too early,
not a second too late,
but just in time to catch her in his arms.
You know if there's a title for this story,
it would be "Caught in Nero's Arms".
What, Nero, do you and Ms. Florence Dela Cruz
have a chance?
Hey, Nero, are you still there?
We're talking to you.
Guys, stop bothering Nero,
and please stop thinking
about our household cook.
Aren't you ashamed?
You're making our cook an object of desire.
Just imagine the scandal
this will bring to our family,
once they find out
we're taking advantage of our staff.
Do you think Grandpa Garp will be happy?
Owen is right.
Stop picking on the new cook.
But still begs the question,
will she last long?
As for me, I can make her quit in one day.
You know what's better, let's welcome her...
The Ferell's style.
I want that.
- Give me some.
- That sounds fun.
It's been a while
since we had a source of amusement.
Remember Chef Boy Logro?
Yes, we made a celebrity chef cry.
How about you, Owen, are you in?
This is ridiculous.
Again, this is just a waste of my time.
I'd rather write my songs.
Then don't.
How about you, Nero?
Are you with us?
You'll enjoy it here.
We'll play a prank on the new cook.
Weirdo.
Stop picking on Nero.
If he gets mad, you're bound to get hurt.
Excuse me, Don Ferell,
I will retire for tonight.
Do you still have something for me to do?
Nothing, you can take the night off.
Thank you, Sir. Good night.
Is it just me, or does that girl, Florence,
look disturbingly familiar?
Well...
Remember there are rumors
that Don Rogelio's granddaughter
is still alive?
Could it be that she's a relative
of the Almeros?
Sir, my ex-boyfriend told me once
that I look like Gretchen Barretto,
but believe it or not, we're not related.
Good one... Good one,
you made me laugh with that.
You don't really think
that you look like Gretchen Barretto.
I'm not joking, Sir.
I honestly believe
that I have a big resemblance
with Ms. Gretchen Barretto,
especially with my angle on the left.
Actually, it's possible.
There is. There's a resemblance.
Well, Sir, if there's nothing else
you want me to do,
then I bid you good night.
Good night, Serafica...
Gretchen Barretto?
Relax, Florence.
Maybe you're just worrying about your father,
that's why, you're having nightmares.
I'm sorry, my child...
But don't worry.
I won't ever stop...
I won't stop until I find Celestina.
- What's that?
- Sushi.
I'm not going to eat that.
Even a stray dog who hasn't eaten for months
won't eat that.
And then you'll ask me to eat that?
Are you crazy?
I was very clear
that what I want is Guimaras mangoes.
Are you okay?
Now if you're really having a hard time
and you can't do it,
I'll understand why you want to resign.
Are you just a dream,
or it will be a reality?
He's cute but is he a weirdo?
Does he sound like a frog?
Kokak, kokak, kokak.
I don't have any desires for him.
None, none, none.
Is there really none?
Have you been here for a long time?
I think you're lost.
Never, ever give up.
You can do it.
What if the person
whose heart you're knocking on
won't let you in his life?
If he really refused to let you in...
I will keep on knocking...
Knock, knock, knock, knock,
until he opens the door.
If he refuses to open the door,
I will destroy the door.
If I need to sneak into the house
or go through the window
just to get in, I will do that.
Or if I need to shout, I will shout,
"Hey, let me in your heart!"
I can feel
there's a lot of space in your heart,
so let me in your heart
for the kind of beauty you're not expecting,
like me.
He will definitely let you in.
He will let me in.
Yes, let her into your heart!
If you won't let her in,
I just don't know about you.